{
    "id": "c68a4f56be59427594b3bd2695de8c8f",
    "title": "Opposites Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Her father is dead but her mother is still ………………………",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "live",
                "alive",
                "living"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The streets are noisy today but they were …………………………. yesterday.",
            "description": "Either silent or quiet is possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "unnoisy",
                "silent",
                "quite",
                "quiet"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Most people are kind but some are ………………………….",
            "description": "Either cruel or unkind is possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "nonkind",
                "unkind",
                "cruel"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Express trains are usually fast but the passenger trains are very ……………………….",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "unfast",
                "slow",
                "loose"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Most country roads are narrow, but roads in the cities are usually …………………………",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "wide",
                "long",
                "deep"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The sea was rough yesterday but today it is ………………………..",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "calm",
                "smooth",
                "silent"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Days are warm and nights are ……………………………. in the deserts.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "cold",
                "sultry",
                ""
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The train arrives at 30 and …………………………. at",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "deserts",
                "departs",
                "leaves"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The judge condemned three of the accused to 7 years of imprisonment while he …………………………….. 2 others.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "convicted",
                "acquitted",
                "condoned"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Kindness is admired but cruelty is ………………………..",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "despised",
                "scorned",
                "spurned"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He hoarded a lot of money but his sons have ……………………………… it.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "accumulated",
                "squandered",
                "proliferated"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He showed no sympathy for the poor. He was full of ………………………..",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "empathy",
                "apathy",
                "cruelty"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}